Finding Aid to the Department of Biological Sciences records CA.MS.00075
Smith College Archives
Department of Biological Sciences records
1901-2001
Smith College Archives
Smith College. Dept. of Biological Sciences.
CA.MS.00075
6.875 linear feet (15 containers)
Records include information regarding committees, courses, exams, department memos, minutes from department meetings, as well as information and publicity regarding lectures and symposiums sponsored by the department. There is also information regarding the Sigma Xi Society and the H.H. Wilder Collection.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections, with the following exception: Box 13 is closed.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
These files were maintained by B. Elizabeth Horner and transferred to the Smith College Archives over a period of time.
Related Material
42. Faculty Biographical Files (various)
34. Office of the Registrar: examinations
12. Symposiums
40. Dean of the Faculty
Scope and Contents
The Biological Sciences Department papers, 1912- present, contain materials regarding committees, courses, (including Genetics, Marine Biology, Paleobiology, and Zoology) exams, department memos, minutes from department meetings, as well as information and publicity regarding lectures and symposiums sponsored by the department. There is also information regarding the Sigma Xi Society and the H.H. Wilder Collection.
Biology--Study and teaching (Higher)--Massachusetts --Northampton.; Wilder, Harris Hawthorne, 1864-1928--Archaeological collections.; Smith College. Dept of Biological Sciences.; Smith College--History--Sources.; Sigma Xi, the Scientific Research Society. Smith College Chapter.
- General (Box 14)
- Administrative Files, 1967-2001 (Box 11, Box 12, Box 13)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 13 is restricted.
- Bird Walk and Department Breakfast, 1954; 1968-69; undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Blakeslee Bequest, 1965; 1970-76 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Budget, 1939-89 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Buildings, Clark Science Center, 1954-2001; undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Committees (Box 1)
  - Ad hoc study group on the recruitment and retainment of women faculty at Smith College, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ad hoc committee to design a research program on women, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ad hoc committee on science, 1958- 64 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Biology Liaison Committee, 1973-76 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Biological Sciences Curriculum, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Building Committee, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Citizen Review Committee: Connecticut River Basin, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - College Grievance Committee, 1973-74 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - College Planning and Resources, 1972-82 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Colloquium Committee, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Committee on Committees, 1975; 1977 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Committee of Six, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Curriculum: Biological Sciences, 1949-69 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Curriculum: Biological Sciences, 1969-84 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Department Organization, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Division III Committee, 1956; 1960; 1975; undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Educational Policy, 1946-78; undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Educational Policy: Subcommittee on curricular review, 1982-83 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Executive Committee, 1967-85 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Faculty Committee Lists, 1940-78 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Faculty Conference Committee, 1965-76; undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Planning Committee, 1970-71 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Finance Committee, 1975; 1979 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Committees: General, 1967; 1976; undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Graduate Study Committee, 1944-74; undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Honorary Degrees, 1953-82 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Honorary Degrees: Correspondence, 1970-82 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Honorary Degrees Committee: Correspondence re: Clara Lynch, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Honors and Independent Programs, 1966-79 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Lecture Committee, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Librarian Faculty Status Committee, 1972-73 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Long Range Planning Committee, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Microscope Committee, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Northampton Ecology Action Committee, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Premedical Advisory Committee, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Presidential Search Committee, 1972-73 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Radiation and Chemical Safety Committee, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Science Advisory Committee, 1962-85 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Science Center Space Committee, 1973; 1980 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Student Committee, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Study Abroad Committee, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Subcommittee on Fringe Benefits, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Tenure and Promotion Committee, 1975-79 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Trustee Planning Committee, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Tutorial Assistance Committee, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Visual Aids Committee, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Youth Committee, 1963-64 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Constitutions: Department of Biological Sciences, Department of Zoology, 1963-82; undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Course Enrollment Lists, 1969-84 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Courses
  - Bio 100, 1967-1980 undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Bio 101, 1967- 68 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Bio 102a, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Bio 104, 1968- 69 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Bio 105-106, 1986-88 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Bio 107, 1967; undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Bio 120a (Microbiology), undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Bio 130a, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Bio 131, 132, 1968-78 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Bio 150, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Bio 195, 1959-60 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Bio 201, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bio 202, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Bio 208, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Bio 210, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Bio 211-212, 1968-69; 1977; undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Bio 214, 1970; 1977 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Bio 230, 1980; undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Bio 231a, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Bio 233, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Bio 274, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Bio 300, 1966-75 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Bio 302, 1978; undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Bio 303b, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Bio 312-313, 1979; undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Bio 321, 1977; undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Bio 327, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Bio 330b, 1967-68 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Bio 333, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Bio 338, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Bio 340, 1966-67; undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Bio 341, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Bio 345, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Bio 402b, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Binder: notes: Zoology 33, 1938-39 (Box 3)
  - Binder: notes: Zoology 37, 1938-39 (Box 3)
  - Courses: General, 1942- (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Courses: Genetics, 1951-69 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Zoology 11, 1964; undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Zoology 12, 1943-59 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Zoology 23a, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Zoology 40b, 1951-56 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Zoology 40b, 1957-62 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Zoology 42b, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Zoology 43a, 1953-54 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Zoology 46, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Zoology 54, 1949-65 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Courses: Unidentified, 1963-1984; undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Courses: Memos and Information, 1941-69 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Courses: Memos and Information, 1970-79 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Courses: New Course Descriptions, 1959-75 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Equipment and Inventory Requests, 1957-85; undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Exams Correspondence, 1965-77; undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Exams: Field A, 1956-82 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Exams: Field B, 1967-75 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Exams: Field C, 1968-69 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Exams: Field E, 1966-74 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Exhibits, 1949-50; 1965; undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Faculty: General, 1967-79 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Faculty: General, 1980-87; undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Faculty Show Scripts, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- General, 1960-69 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- General, 1970-74 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- General, 1975-85; undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Graduate Study, 1940-82 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Grants, 1963-2000 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Honors, 1941-49 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Honors, 1951-59 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Honors, 1960-668Honors1971-80 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Honors, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Honors, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Horticulturalist, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Lectures, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Blakeslee Lecture, 1955-56 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Lectures, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Blakeslee Lecture, 1965-66 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Lectures, 1965-66 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Lectures, 1966-67 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Lectures, 1967-68 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Lectures, 1968-69 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Lectures, 1969-70 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Lectures, 1970-71 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Lectures, 1971-72 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Lectures, 1972-73 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Lectures, 1973-74 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Lectures, 1974-75 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Lectures, 1975-76 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Lectures, 1976-77 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Lectures, 1977-78 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Lectures, 1978-79 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Lectures, 1979-80 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Lectures, 1980-81 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Lectures, 1981-82 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Lectures, 1982-83 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Lectures, 1983-84 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Lectures, 1984-85 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Lectures, 1985-86 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Lectures, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Lectures, undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Library Materials, 1940; 1967-79 (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Lists of Majors, 1940-60 (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Lists of Majors, 1962-69 (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Lists of Majors, 1970-75 (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Lists of Majors, 1975-80 (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Marine Science (Five Colleges), 1972-99 (Box 7, Folder 33)
- Memos, 1966-77; 1981 (Box 7, Folder 34)
- Minor, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 35)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1938-39 (Box 7, Folder 36)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1939-40 (Box 7, Folder 37)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1940-41 (Box 7, Folder 38)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1941-42 (Box 7, Folder 39)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1942-43 (Box 7, Folder 40)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1943-44 (Box 7, Folder 41)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1944-45 (Box 7, Folder 42)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1945-46 (Box 7, Folder 43)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1946-47 (Box 7, Folder 44)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1947-48 (Box 7, Folder 45)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1948-49 (Box 7, Folder 46)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1949-50 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1950-51 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1951-52 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1952-53 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1953-54 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1954-55 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1955-56 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1956-57 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1957-58 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1958-59 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1959-60 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1960-61 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1961-62 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1962-63 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1963-64 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1965-66 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1966-67 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1967-68 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1968-69 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1969-70 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1970-71 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1971-72 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1972-73 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1973-74 (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1974-75 (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1975-76 (Box 8, Folder 26)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1977-78 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1978-79 (Box 8, Folder 28)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1979-80 (Box 8, Folder 29)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1981-82 (Box 8, Folder 30)
- Minutes: Department Meetings, 1986-87 (Box 8, Folder 31)
- Miscellaneous, 1937-69 (Box 8, Folder 32)
- Miscellaneous, 1970-79 (Box 8, Folder 33)
- Miscellaneous, 1980- 84 (Box 8, Folder 34)
- Miscellaneous, undated (Box 8, Folder 35)
- Paleobiology, 1982-85. undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Photographs: Classes, 1901; 1970; 1982-88; undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Premedical Society, 1950-80; undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Pre-1966 Reorganization, 1960-62; undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Publications, 1939-52 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Research, 1982-85 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Revision and Departmental Reorganization, 1966-68 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Revision of the Major, 1963-77 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Sigma Xi, 1943-89; undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Sigma Xi Correspondence, 1948-80 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Space Requests, 1968-69 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Symposiums
  - Photographs, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Society for the Study of Development and Growth, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Connecticut Valley Student Scientific Conference, 1952-53 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Four College Blakeslee Biological Conference, 1955-64; undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Conference on Women in Science, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Vanderbilt Symposium: Announcements, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Vanderbilt Symposium: Articles and Clippings, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Vanderbilt Symposium: SAQ Articles, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Vanderbilt Symposium: Correspondence, 1968-69 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Vanderbilt Symposium: Notes, 1968- 69 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Vanderbilt Symposium: Symposium Scripts, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Vanderbilt Symposium: Speakers: Archer, E. James, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Vanderbilt Symposium: Speakers: Cole, Lamont C., 1968 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Vanderbilt Symposium: Speakers: Holling, C.S, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Vanderbilt Symposium: Speakers: Keith, Hastings, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Symposium: Mill River Project, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Symposium: Structure of Matter, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- H.H. Wilder Collection
  - Clippings, 1912-13; undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence to H.H. Wilder, 1902; 1917 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1917; undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1971-76 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1977-84 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1989-99 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Displays and Exhibits, 1982-98 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Human Skulls Inventory, 1983-83 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Mounted Birds and Human Skeletons, 1981-86 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Museum of Art Acquisitions, 1984-91 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Obituary: Whipple, Sarah Wheaton, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Special Studies: Ryan, Marilyn, "The Wilder Collection of Southwest Indian Pottery", 1996 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Negatives of Skulls, undated (Box Binder)